<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ManyClasses</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ManyClasses</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ManyClasses: A model for abstracting generalizable research principles from different learning contexts</title>
      <link>/updates/manyclasses-a-model-for-abstracting-generalizable-research-principles-from-different-learning-contexts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/manyclasses-a-model-for-abstracting-generalizable-research-principles-from-different-learning-contexts/</guid>
      <description>Note: This post was originally presented as a submission to replicate.education: A Workshop on Large Scale Education Replication as part of the Educational Data Mining 2018 conference.
Research on learning has unique strengths when conducted in authentic educational contexts, as compared with laboratory contexts. Principal among these, an experiment embedded in a real class will provide a more legitimate measure of a learning activity’s benefit for real educational outcomes than an experiment with a synthetic learning task and materials (Motz et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ManyClasses 1: Timing of Feedback</title>
      <link>/projects/many-classes-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/many-classes-1/</guid>
      <description>We will focus on a specific instructional practice: the provision of immediate feedback on student assignments. We opted to focus on immediate feedback for several reasons: (1) it is highly recommended for improving student learning in STEM fields (Pashler et al., 2007), (2) it is a common component of most classes and will not represent a deviation from normal practice, (3) instructors must decide (implicitly or explicitly) when to provide feedback to their students and they need evidence-based recommendations to inform that decision, and (4) there are controversial claims that delayed feedback is better than immediate feedback, which directly contrasts with current recommendations to educators (see Butler &amp;amp; Woodward, 2018).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>